Ismael Espindola

Web Development and Visual Designer.

I am looking for my first IT job. I have been improving my skills as a web developer for more than two years, and I have more than 15 years as a graphic designer. I want to be able to contribute my experience and skills in innovative and challenging projects, being part of first-class work teams.

Contact	Relevant coursework	
La Rioja, Argentina +54 9 380 4646916	Node.js: Essential LinkedIn Learning, backend web development	Oct. 2020
EspiFreelancer.com	Node.js: Practical LinkedIn Learning, backend web development	Nov. 2020
twitter.com/ EspiFreelancer	JavaScript: Essential LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer	Aug. 2020
github.com/ EspiFreelancer	JavaScript: Advanced - Regular Expressions LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer	Aug. 2020
in linkedin.com/in/	JavaScript: Advanced - Best Practices LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer	Aug. 2020
EspiFreelancer	SQL: Essential LinkedIn Learning, backend web development	Oct. 2020
Skill	Learn relational database design LinkedIn Learning, backend web development	Oct. 2020
Python	Amazon Web Services Practitioners Ministry of Planning and Industry, backend web development	Jul. 2019
JavaScript Django	Web development: Automated quality control LinkedIn Learning, software development skills	Oct. 2020
PostgreSQL	Introduction to Software Testing National University of La Rioja (UNLAR), software development skills	Oct. 2019
MySQL/MariaDB	GitHub for developers LinkedIn Learning, full-stack web developer	Nov. 2020
IBM/Watson	Learn SCRUM LinkedIn Learning, software development skills	Aug. 2020
Testing	Scrum: Roles LinkedIn Learning, software development skills	Aug. 2020
	Teamwork LinkedIn Learning, software development skills	Nov. 2020
	Events and competitions	
	Mayatana Bahind the Code 2020 IBM Latin America	A

Maratona Behind the Code 2020 | IBM Latin America

Aug./Sep. 2020

Eight real company business challenges in five weeks. Using:

- Watson Assistant
- Watson Knowkedge Studio
- Watson Natural Language Understanding
- Watson Machine Learning
- Machine Learning (with Jupyter Notebooks)
- Feature engineering

Courses without certificate

Python pildorasinformaticas, POO	Jul. 2017
Django mozilla.org - developers, backend web development	Dec. 2017
Django REST codigofacilito, backend web development	Oct. 2019
PostgreSQL Tecnología Binaria, backend web development	Aug. 2019
Vue.js 2 Bluuweb, frontend web development	Jan. 2020
Git makigas, practical software development skills	Feb. 2019
Education	
National University of La Rioja (UNLAR), Argentina Industrial engineering (three years, unfinished career)	2001 - 2004
Professional Experience	
Graphic designer, Chimichanga	2014 - 2019

Own entrepreneurship with partner.

- Adaptation of images for printing on clothing.
 - · Photo retouching.
 - Logo creation, event packaging, brochures, etc
 - Preparation of jobs for printing on different media.
 - Color separation for screen printing, image preparation for cutting plotter.
- Traditional and digital illustration.

Graphic designer, Telestar

2003 - 2018

Service provider.

- Technical maintenance of computer equipment, networks, printers and photocopiers.
- Multiple equipment printing management.
- Preparing documents for printing.
- Creation of posters, brochures, photo retouching, video editing.

Radiophonic technical operator, National University of La Rioja (UNLAR)

2002 - 2003

Live equipment operation. Editing and post-production.

- Radio broadcast programming (Automatic Satellite Connection, entry of programmed advertising guidelines, opening / closing of radio programs and content for re-broadcast, independent musical content of the program).
- Technical maintenance and repair of equipment.
- Active participation in production teams.
- Performance as an assistant sound engineer.

This CV is online and always updated at: EspiFreelancer.github.io